ERIK KIMSEY

// SOFTWARE ENGINEER

erikkimsey.com

T: 540 278 4525 E: kimseyerik@gmail.com

github.com/erikkimsey linkedin.com/in/erikkimsey

As a passionate, tenacious, and creative engineer, I use the right tools and architecture for the job. But, I specialize in full-stack engineering using ES6/7, React, NodeJS/ExpressJS, and SQLite, with a passion for building intuitive, performant, and beautiful technology.

SKILLS

Full-Stack Engineering

- · JavaScript, React, NextJS
- Redux
- CSS3, Sass, Styled-Componets
- HTML5
- NodeJS, Express API
- Relational & NoSQL database design
- GraphQL
- · Apollo-Server / -Client
- Python / Diango
- Webpack
- · Test-Driven Development
- Bootstrap
- Redis
- Web Audio API
- Web Sensor APIs
- P5.is
- D3.js

Languages

- Javascript (ES6/7)
- Python
- · SQL
- GraphQL
- Java (Android)
- Processing
- · C/C++

Design Tools

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD

Misc. (experience varying)

- React-Native
- Propellerhead Reason
- Abelton Live
- Audacity
- Blender
- Unity3D
- JUCE
- Arduino
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe AfterEffects

WORK EXPERIENCE

9/2018

NEXTLEVEL / KARDION

Front-End Engineer

(HTML5, Sass, Bootstrap)

 Per design specifications, helped build responsive website for medtech firm, Kardion GmbH

6/2018

NEXTLEVEL / B612 DESIGN

Front-End Engineer

(Angular 4 & D3)

 Contributed to the development of an interactive guilloche for use by a Stuttgart design firm, B612

1/2018

RAINCROW

Back-End Engineer contractor (NodeJS & Redis)

 Contributed to the early-stage engineering of a Node server and Redis database supporting the activity of a MMORPG (Covens)

10/2016 - 6/2017

CHARTIQ

JavaScript Engineer

(JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, & AngularJS)

- Helped implement "ProCharts" in a ChartIQ client's application
- Contributed to performance upgrades, using JavaScript, to ChartIQ's flagship financial-charting solution
- Contributed to public-facing documentation

2012 - 2016

ROSETTA STONE

Studio Recording Technician/ Product Support

- Monitored and recorded Live Studio Sessions.
- Created training materials for Studio Recording Technician role.
- Helped Consumers Troubleshoot Rosetta Stone software issues

EDUCATION

2018 - 2019

COMPUTER SCIENCE

Lambda School

Curriculum:

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Database and RESTful API Design
- Programming paradigms (Declarative, Imperative, and Procedural)
- · Software Design Patterns
- Single-Page Application Development
- Algorithm Analysis
- Data Structures
- Theory of Computation
- · Computer Architecture
- Cellular Automata
- Version Control
- Agile (Scrum and Kanban) and Waterfall techniques

2017

COMPUTER SCIENCE

osu

- · Object-Oriented Programming in C++
- Discrete Maths

2012

WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT (CERT)

Blue Ridge Community College

- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java
- · Graphic Design Concepts
- Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

2006 - 2010 PHILOSOPHY (BS)

James Madison University
Minors: creative writing & design

 Phi Sigma Tau Philosophy Honors Society Member